Register of the John Kohnen Honey papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John Kohnen Honey papers
1917-1919
79063
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Diaries, letters, correspondence, clippings, postcards, and photographs relating to the American Ambulance Service attached to French Army forces in France during World War I. As a whole, the collection depicts John Kohnen Honey's time in the American Field Service during World War I.
Honey, John Kohnen, 1896-1978.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1979.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Biographical note
March 16, 1896 Born, North Dakota
1915-1917 Student at Stanford University
1917 Enlisted into the United States Army as a Private First Class
1917 Volunteered as a member of the American Ambulance Field Service in France
1919 Dischraged from military service
August 2, 1978 Died, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Collection include diaries, correspondence, clippings, postcards and photographs relating to the American Ambulance Service attached to French Army forces in France from 1917 to 1919. As a whole the collection details Honey’s time in the American Field Service during World War I. Through diaries and correspondence, Honey provides a glimpse into a life of a soldier within the American Field Service. Photographs and negatives depict scenes of destruction, war and everyday life of the American Ambulance Service.
American Field Service.; France. Armée.; World War, 1914-1918--France.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care.
- Personal Papers, 1917-1919
  Scope and Contents
  Contains military papers, letters, diaries, and newspaper clippings related to the American Field Service from 1917-1919. As an enlisted soldier assigned to the American Ambulance Service, Honey described the conditions of war in letters to family members and personal diaries. Pieces of the diaries have been typed out. Articles about Honey’s service were published in several issues of the Gresham Outlook, a hometown newspaper from Gresham, Oregon.
  - Military papers, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Diaries, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Typed diary, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Photographs and postcards, 1917-1919
  Photographs include image of American and French troops, the ambulance service of the American Field Service, and scenes of destruction in France during World War I. Collection contains over 600 prints and 150 negatives.
  - Postcards, 1918 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Photo album, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Negatives, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Prints, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 2:2-5)